RAJAT GOGNA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dublin, Ireland | +353-89-484-3883 | https://rgog.github.io | rajat.gogna30@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a Master's student at Trinity College Dublin, & have 3 years of proven experience in software development. I commit to design & develop web-apps engineered for excellence. Primarily experienced in Java, SQL & ReactJS, I wish to apply my strong analytical & technical skills, to deliver reliable, feature-rich, & user-friendly web applications

CKILLS

- Java | Spring Boot | Hibernate | Python | JavaScript (ES6) | ReactJS | HTML | CSS | Tomcat | RabbitMQ | Microservices |
 REST | SQL | PL/SQL | NoSQL | Oracle | Maven | Agile | DevOps | Continuous Integration (CI) | Continuous Delivery (CD) |
 Test Driven Development (TDD) | Extreme Programming | Git | Multithreading | Database Management | Kafka | Redux |
- Communication | Problem Solving | Teamwork | Strategic Planning | Time Management |

WORK EXPERIENCE

SYSTEMS ENGINEER, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES | (September 2018 – July 2019)

- Liaised with managers to translate business needs into feasible technical solutions, & propose process improvements
- Saved >\$100k of immediate system overhaul costs by proposing & developing new REST API endpoints for enhancing a legacy application, as per changing business needs
- Revamped inventory management, & shipment modules of an application to optimize order management
- Eliminated human error, & slashed efforts by 90%, by automating analysis & restructuring of unstructured, erroneous data
- Ranked first in the annual evaluation conducted for TCS-AbbVie team

ASSISTANT SYSTEMS ENGINEER, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES | (September 2016 – August 2018)

- Proposed & implemented automation of routine data migration activities, improving efficiency by 50%
- Developed bug fixes & system enhancements using various technologies Java, ReactJS, PL/SQL, Python
- Slashed manual effort by 95% (60 mins to ~3 mins) for a monitor & alert activity through automation
- Created fail-safe & self-healing jobs using shell & SQL scripts, to ensure system continuity in high availability research labs
- Earned the title: "Star of Learners Group" for graduating top of the class in the company's learning program
- Mentored 2 batches of ~100 associates each on soft skills, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), & software development frameworks - Agile & SDLC

EDUCATION

MSc. Computer Science, Trinity College Dublin, University of Dublin | (September 2019 – Ongoing)

- Developed a scalable, offline-first, web-app, using Python (Django) & Angular, following DevOps practices & tools
- Learned core workings of machine learning algorithms, & techniques to optimize them
- Developed a prototype for a Body Area Networking protocol using AWS Lambda, & other cloud resources
- Created multiple interactive & dynamic visualization dashboards as part of the data visualization module

Bachelor of Technology, Manay Rachna International University | (July 2012 – August 2016)

- Scholarship holder
- Being a founding member of the Innovation & Incubation Center (IIC), garnered exceptional leadership skills
- Semi-finalist inter-college group discussion event with >2500 participants from top universities of India
- Working on cross-disciplinary projects with students from different fields of engineering, I took home the values of teamwork & team-building

CERTIFICATIONS

- Spring Boot 2.0 Essential Training LinkedIn Learning
- React.JS Essential Training LinkedIn Learning
- R Programming
 Coursera Johns Hopkins University
- ITIL Foundation
 Peoplecert

- Applied Machine Learning in Python Coursera - University of Michigan
- Quality Practitioner Associate Plus American Society of Quality (ASQ)

MOST PROUD OF

- Consistent Performance recognized through various awards & accolades; "Technical Excellence" & "Star of the Month"
- With Persistence & Determination, I became the youngest developer to own the biggest enterprise application in our team
- High Adaptability, & quick Learnability, I exhibited, while learning niche technologies required in new project proposals